

BRIEF

Deep in area of Digital Marketing, Internet, Retailing Industry, I have been working as a coding developer for 7 years+, as a delivery leader and a solution architect for at least 4 years, and as a team leader and project manager for at least 4 years with experience of from 0 to 1 tech team startup.

I do well in managing team relationship including teams' emotions, expectations, team work, etc. I am also an excellent troubleshooter who is good at issue analytics and idea making to solve the problems with a 'can-do' attitude and as a great multitasker.

I have 4 years + clients facing experience which is proven to be applicable at pitching tech project, contacting and cooperating with clients' IT as a expert and a solution architect, replying to clients concerns, solving clients' problems and comforting client in calm-down way.

I'm a crazy lover in areas of technology, data science, product, managing, creative and digital marketing. I'm mainly targeting at technology and tech team and with full passion doing tech innovation researching and application.

CONTACT

PHONE: 17721616896

EMAIL:

servantdjrk@hotmail.com

DAVID DING

EDUCATION

Nanjing University of Information and Science Technology Information & Computing Science (Mathematic Major) 2012.09 – 2016.07 Bachelor's Degree of Science

- Merit student with a totally hands-on graduation design of a PHP Web-Based Navigation App using an enhanced Dijkstra Algorithm, of which enhancing the Dijkstra Algorithm is a highlighted point in this design.
- Passed Cisco Certified Internet Expert Routing &Switch (CCIE) at school.
- Math-based Course: Mathematical Analysis, Advanced Algebra, Analytic Geometry, Probability Statistics, Discrete mathematics, Functions of Real Variable, Functions of Complex Variables, Ordinary Differential Equations, Partial Differential Equations
- CS-Based Course: MATLAB Programming, Numerical Calculation Method, Operations Research, Computer Network, C language, Java Language, JSP Web Page Programming, Compilation Principle, Algorithm and Data Structure, Database Application Technology, Software Test Principle, Operating System

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dentus · Merkle Inc Senior Technical Engineer 2016.01 – 2019.11

Merkle Inc is a Dentus Company and is a Data-Driven Performance Martketing Company. Merkle provides full eco-service with data technology, including database operating, Business Statistics, Analytics for online and/or offline retailors to help them win in modern market.

The team where I worked is digital marketing and analytics. We served a lot famous retailors in industries including Consuming, Luxury, Accessory, Insurance, Food, Vehicles etc., We are dedicated to using tracking tech and data solution to meet clients' requirements of digital data tracking, UX experience optimization, product promotion application etc. to extend business chances and win high fame, high praise and high profit from market.

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked as a self-starter software developer to create business value for team and clients
- Managed project members and project lifecycle
- Developed and researched on new capabilities and new trends related to data tech field.
- Provided consulting service on digital tech solutions and stay hands-on on architecture design and construction.
- Took client facing jobs including project pitching, integration, meeting collaboration.

Lingyu Information Technology Company Engineering & Product & Test Team Manager

2020.3 - 2021.05

Lingyu Company is a Chinese startup company which was founded at the end of 2019, that provides service for enterprises and organizations in education, government and manufacturing industry, with OA

HOBBIES

Touring
Food & Cooking
Ball Sports
Reading & Watching
Designing

solutions, big data solutions, things of internet solutions. It focuses on Technology and Data, and its tech team grows fast to support Solutions Business.

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Built up Engineering & Product & Test Team from 0 to 1 with almost all functions within 6 mons
- Managed Engineering & Product & Test Team in shaped ways of work process and study methodology.
- Participated, led and assisted in overall Tech Project Lifecycle, including pre-sale solution, project design, project execution, project test, UAT, Maintenance
- Coached and advised junior engineers in tech enhancement and career development.
- Recruiting tech talent for long-term development.
- Hands-on coding and architecting
- Clients' facing job including setting up and updating the solutions on their env, reporting project progress to clients' key stakeholder, troubleshooting and collaborating with clients' IT.

Impact Radius Inc. Technical Solutions Manager 2021.05 – 2021.08

Impact Radius Inc. is a solution provider that is devoted to building up a partnership bridge between brands and media partner, with Partnership Cloud (Formerly known as Impact Radius), a SaaS Platform, to promote performance marketing and help brands and media partners win business.

Impact Greater China just started it business in China in 2019 and has been having booming increasing on sale and market share till now. It signed hundreds of brands and many media partners in china. And it is really growing faster than you could imagine.

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Providing tech support and solutions on clients' demand over pre-sale phase.
- Leading Solution Architects and Onboarding Team, to support clients' integration tech, and collaborate with sale team and customer success team to get client's service process smooth.
- Leading Engineering & Product Team to develop new features of Partnership Cloud and any other existing Impact products for China market.
- Recruiting, mentoring and managing tech talents for tech team's long-term development.

Ariel Kene Apparel Co.; Ltd Co-founder&CTO 2021.09 – 2022.06

Ariel Kene is an international apparel trade company which was founded by me and my friend. Ariel Kene is aim to build up its own brand and impact the market with online marketing strategy. Due to negative marketing expectations and COVI -19 flow from March to May in Shanghai, the company was claimed close-down in June of 2022.

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Buliding up tech team to support online marketing including official online shop, Amazon US, Amazon CA, Amazon Japan from 0 to 1.
- Managing, coaching tech team & product team & operating team
- Asissting CEO operating the online marketing with marketing tool with Google Analytics, Impact Partnership Cloud, Facebook Ad, Google Ads.

- Build up data hub in order to integrate CRM data, website analytics data, ads performance data together to build up performance marketing system and inspect market trend to help Ariel Kene brand upsell.
- Hiring Top Talent for tech and product team.

Simon Electric (China) Co., Ltd Senior Software Development Lead 2022.7 – Present

Simon is a manufacture company who produce switch and lamps and lanterns and is a famous Spanish brand and a forerunner in the area.

I am working in IT dept. which takes charge of the whole IT Solution of the company. We take the development of Inner Site i9c.simon.com.cn which contains extended functions development from U9 ERP System to serve other depts' producing work.

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Work as a main developer and a lead with 3 members and take charge of Purchase Process Function Including Purchase Request, Request for Quotations, Compare Price, Stocking in and Stocking Out, Transportation.
- Take charge of SQL Query optimization, architecture optimization, process optimization, foundation code optimization.
- Take charge of collaborating with other depts about new IT development request, scheduling project plan, control project progress and risk management.

A Real Contributor of Github/Gitee/StackFlow Long term

I am always a new tech lover and system practitioner. From my start to work, I have pushed forward thousands of tech questions and solutions in github, Stackflow and many other tech forum. From 2019 to now, I even have my vision on data and marketing and construct the image of data cloud which is shown at my first project experience and have build up the fundamental architecture and equipment and upload the project to gitee.

I like new tech and new thinking with Marketing and Retailing industry. I will continuously think about the most frontier tech and solution archtecture

SKILLS

Programming & Architecting

- Java Spring Family: Spring MVC Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Cloud, main class Middleware (Eureka, Gateway, Ribbon), Maven/Gradle,
- Programming Language: C#, Java, Python, JavaScript (Node.is), PHP, Swift, Objective-c, Scala
- Template Engine: Ejs, Free marker
- Other Framework: Express, Vue.js, Quasar (Based on Vue), Bootstrap, jQuery, CodeMirror, d3, Echarts, Razor Page
- Database & Middleware & Web Service: MySQL, Postgre SQL, Oracle DB, Kafka, Redis, Hadoop, HBase, Nginx, Tomcat, Docker
- Flow Processing Engine: Spark, Fllnk
- Version Control: Git, GitHub.com/Gitee.com, Gitlab,TFS

- Testing Tool & Tracker: JMeter Cluster, Postman, Python Automation, Swagger UI, (TDD) Jasmine, Jira, 禅道
- Cloud Product: Windows/Linux VM, Google Cloud, K8s, Huawei Cloud, Aliyun Cloud, Azure, AWS

Product & Prototype & UI UX Design

- Axure
- Microsoft Visio
- XMind
- Google Diagram

Tracking Tech & Analytics & Marketing Tools

- Adobe Marketing Cloud: Analytic, Target, Audience Management, Launch (DTM), Mobile Tracking
- Google Analytics 360: Analytics, Audience Manager, GTM, Google Optimize, Firebase for Mobile Tracking
- A/B Test: Optimizely, Adobe Target, Google Optimize,
- Impact Cloud: Partnership Cloud, Activate (Internet Pop Star Marketing)
- DMP: Adobe Audience Management, Google Audience Manager, Oracle Bluekai (Core Tag)
- Commerce Solutions: Shopify / Branch

Project Management

- Waterfall Management
- Agile Management & CI CD
- Budget Management & Pricing, Workload Calculation

Working Tactics

- Multiple Task
- Resource Allocation, Project Plan, Cross Team Collaboration
- Self-starter, Self-Disciplined
- Critical thinking & Comprehensive Thinking & Strategic Thinking,
 Think as a marketer, a brand owner, a team forerunner
- Presenter & Analytical Thinker & Story Teller.

Team & People

- Career Advisor
- Emotion and Feeling Mastery
- Work Enablement & Team Motivation & Idea Lighting
- Listener & Thinker & Communicator

CERTIFICATIONS

Adobe Certified SiteCatalyst Processing Rules Test

Certification Date: Apr 2017 - Present

License: ADB402182

Google Analytics

Certification Date: Sep 2016 - Present

Cisco Certified Network Professional Certification Date: Oct 2014 – Present

CCIE R&S

Certification Date: Mar 2015 – Mar 2017 License: #47820

CET-6: 533 CET-4: 574

ACCOUNTS & PROJECTS

SOFTWARE & SYSTEM & DATA APPLICATION

Data Cloud – Recommendation Engine (Private Open-Source Project on gitee.com)

Duration: 2020 - present

Contents

 Developing a big data cloud platform to meet growing requirements of real-time or low latency computing and optimized data insight and data application.

Design:

- This system designed have these features as below:
- Millisecond-level response
- Visit lifecycle based real-time computing
- High concurrency, high tolerance
- TB-level Data Storage
- Customized Online Modelling Engine Base on TensorFlow
- Real time computing allows some computing latency. But responding data to user should be fast as possible.
- Usually within 15s after a user action a time, a result should be calculated out and presented to user when a user does something next time.
- Large scalable, sub system separately and smoothly running
- Long term big data BI service

Module code has been uploaded to https://gitee.com/davidjackson-luther-king/data-cloud.

Code will be continuously iteratively developed soon.

Simon i9c System

Duration:2022.7- present

Account: Simon

Contents

- Redesign site theme and optimize home page layout of i9c.simon.com.cn
- Optimize purchase related functions and complete new development request.
- Lead team to optimize SQL Query, Server Architecture and old function codes.

Office System/Purchase System/Human Resource System/ KPI System

Duration: 2020.11 – 2021.6

Account: Nanchang Military Academy

Contents:

- Taking charge of project researching, interpreting business requirements to tech points, working out project and solution architecture, tech stack choosing.
- Project Management through full project lifespan, including project pitching, business analysis, product design, project plan, budget plan, project progress control, client reporting, project execution, UAT
- Collaborate with client on project resource reallocating, onsite reporting and execution, clients' enhanced requirements auditing, maintenance planning.

Estate Assets Management System

Duration: 2021.01 - 2021.4

Account: Nantong Guorong Estate Assets

Contents:

- Designed and led the team to developing and testing a management system for an estate asset account.
- Managed project progress and reduce project risk.
- On-site delivery, reporting and maintaining job

MetLife - Insurance Broker Promotion System

Duration: 2019.08 - 2019.11

Account: MetLife

Contents:

- Designed and developed a near real-time update content traffic system to help marketers gain brokers and indirectly push selling insurance products.
- Managed project progress and reduce project risk.

IKEA – Product Recommendation System

Duration: 2018.06 - 2018.09

Account: IKEA Contents:

- Designed and developed a daily rolling product recommendation with analyst and statisticians.
- Managed project progress and reduce project risk.

Merkle – Digital Marketing Data Solution Platform

Duration: 2017 - 2019 Account: Merkle Contents:

> This is an inner productize platform and it is for long term under development. I was working as a core technician focus on data QA Semi-Automation, and data reports.

Mobile App Tracking

Duration: 2017 Account: Merkle Contents:

> Developed Adobe Mobile Tracking and Google Firebase Mobile Tracking demo for pitch.

MARKETING ANALTYICS SOLUTIONS

Impact Base Projects:

Durations: 2021.05 - now

Accounts: Parzin, Minstinct, Bookey, Cowinaudio, Fansidea, Anycubic

Banggood, Adidas

Contents:

- Help clients onboarding Impact Partnership Cloud integration successfully, mainly with website, mini program, Mobile App
- Make sure actions or orders attribution correct.

Adobe Based Projects

Duration: 2016 - 2018

Account: Estee Lauder, NBA CN (Main Website & QMQ), LEVI's CN, FCA

US, FCA APAC, AIA

Contents:

 Led and developed Adobe digital marketing solution including tagging audit, data QA, Solution Design, implementation, Testing (Manual & Automation), Maintenance, Cross domain data Integration, data application service.

Google Based Projects

Duration: 2016 - 2018

Account: Abbott, Wall Street English, Victory Secret, Arrow CN

Contents:

 Led and developed google digital marketing solution tagging audit, data QA, Solution Design, implementation, Testing (Manual & Automation), Maintenance, Cross domain data Integration, data application service.

.

DMP Based Project

Duration:2018

Account: Singapore Airline, Officeworks AU

Contents:

Implemented Audience Managing Tool or A/B Test to site.

 Help analysts build up audience segment and give ads dispatching recommendations.